## **Yiannis Nennes**

Cambridge, United Kingdom, yiannis@nenn.es

#### **Profile**

I'm a software engineer who's excited about great UX and clean code. I enjoy a culture of helping people, sharing knowledge and delivering valuable and maintainable products. Most of my experience is in the FE with React, but I happily take on any technical challenge.

# **Experience**

```
Jan 2023 - Apr 2023 Dojo, Software Engineer
```

Made the Dojo RMS (restaurant management system) simpler and more powerful, mainly using React/GraphQL. Most proud about consolidating 3 core pages into a unified experience, with improved UI and features. This is expected to add significant value to the app, while removing large amounts of legacy code.

```
Aug 2022 - Jan 2023 Ziglu, Staff Engineer
```

Faced with the challenge of an overcomplicated ReactNative app, I proposed and lead the initiative to introduce a shim service. I integrated it with the event-driven BE architecture and introduced GraphQL to push updates to the app. Unfortunately the Robinhood aquisition was cancelled, and most employees were made redundant.

```
May 2016 - Jul 2022 eBay, Member of Technical Staff
```

Built fantastic eBay experiences! Worked with Java/Kotlin in Spring(MVC I Boot)/Android, Swift in iOS and JS/TS in React/Marko. Most proud about architecting the eBay <a href="mailto:shipping">shipping</a> web app (in TS/React/Redux/Reselect) and the native shipping experience service (in Kotlin/SpringBoot). Created and released multiple internal tools, mentored and managed junior developers. Worked closely with POs and designers to ensure that we build the right features the right way.

```
Apr 2017 - Dec 2018 CodeYourFuture, Mentor
```

Volunteered to enable refugees change their future through web development training and career coaching. Taught part of the curriculum, helped with 1:1 coding sessions and guided

many through their successful interview journey.

```
Oct 2012 - May 2016 Fivium, Application Developer
```

Developed and maintained complex workflow-based systems for the UK government. Heavily used Oracle SQL, PL/SQL (for all the business logic) and XML (see <u>FOXopen framework</u>). Designed and built a report generation web application, which collected production data from multiple DBs, combined them, applied statistical calculations and allowed for generating PDF reports (using Jasper templates).

### **Education**

2005 - 2010 University of Patras, Computer Engineering and Informatics

This is a 5 year diploma in Computer Science, Hardware Engineering and Software Engineering. Completed most of the subjects (~85%), left **before graduating**.

2000 - 2005 University of Piraeus, BSc in Industrial Management

This is focused on Economics, Management and Production Technology. It gave me the fundamentals for managing a production facility.

### **Interests**

Mainly spending time with my amazing cat. A bit of whittling, archery, tinkering with computers.